It is paramount that we recover the final four Iacon relics...
找到最后四个铁堡遗物是我们的当务之急
the Omega keys.
它们是“终极之钥”
Keys?
钥匙？
To what?
能打开什么？
The regeneration of our home planet.
我们的故乡涅重生的关键…
A tomb.
一座古墓？
One known to contain the remains of Primes.
据说这座古墓里长眠着一位元祖领袖！
At long last, the power of the Primes belongs to me!
终于 领袖的力量现在属于我了！
Four sets of coordinates from Alpha Trion remain encrypted.
钛师傅的讯息里还剩下四组加密坐标
It is logical to conclude that each corresponds to the location of one of the Omega keys.
我们可以推断出那就是终极之钥的位置
My first creation,
这是我的第一件作品
fashioned from the very blood of Unicron.
以宇宙大帝之血铸就
I call it the Dark Star Saber.
我称之为暗黑星辰剑
The relic. now!
快点 交出遗物
Oh, you mean this? Finders keepers.
哦 你是说这个？谁找到归谁！
You should have seen Optimus Prime's face
你该看看擎天柱当时的表情！
when his precious Star Saber shattered like glass and, with it his dreams of an Autobot victory.
当他的宝贝星辰剑连同他的美梦 和汽车人的胜利一起如玻璃般破碎之时
Granted,
毫无疑问
Optimus will be more determined than ever to discover
擎天柱抢占剩余遗物的决心会更加坚决
Ah, very good.
啊 很好
I see you have decoded the next set of coordinates.
看来你已破译出了下一个坐标
Way to step things up, Soundwave.
真有你的 声波
I do hope this Iacon relic is something less sacred and more profane,
我真希望这回别又是什么神圣之物
like an electro-disruptor cannon.
最好是电磁毁灭炮之类的
We could use one of those.
那会更加实用
Indeed, Knockout.
说的不错 击倒
Dreadwing, report to the bridge immediately.
骇翼 立刻向舰桥报告！
Please, lord Megatron,
我恳求您 威震天陛下
allow me the honor of retrieving this relic for you.
将找回遗物的荣耀赐予属下
I'm surprised you would risk your finish so soon after your accident.
我很惊讶 那次“事故”之后 你这么快就无所畏惧了么？
Nonetheless, I remain unconvinced that you are the best choice for the task
尽管如此 我还是反复劝说自己 你是这次任务的最佳人选
since you failed to secure the phase shifter.
虽然你没能拿回相位仪
I lacked the proper tools.
那是因为我缺乏合适的工具
But since Soundwave's currently occupied,
既然声波现在抽不出身
I can't imagine he'll mind if I borrow this...
我想您不会介意我借用一下这个
So that I might better secure your prize
用它来带回您的战利品
and heap some hurt on the Autobots.
同时狠狠地教训那些汽车人！
I'm gonna be a great warrior someday, like Optimus.
总有一天 我要成为像擎天柱那样伟大的战士
Well, train hard and gain some wisdom along the way,
没错…好好学习 天天向上
and I'm sure it'll happen.
你一定能如愿以偿的
Oh, it will. It's my destiny.
哦 那当然 这可是我的宿命
How so?
何以见得？
Well, one minute I'm on security detail at Iacon.
你看 一分钟前我还在铁堡当保安
The next, I wake up on the other side of the galaxy
下一分钟我醒来 就到了银河系的另一边
to find myself under Optimus' command.
成为了擎天柱的部下
I mean, what are the chances, right?
我是说 这种事可不常见吧？
Things happen for a reason.
这…这一定事出有因
We get it, Smokescreen.
我们懂了 烟幕
You're special. We're lucky to have you.
你是特别的 有你在是我们的造化
All I'm really saying is,
我真正想说的只是…
I've come a long way, and this is one opportunity I don't plan on messing up.
我跋山涉水来到这里 可不想辜负了这个机会
Autobots, the next Iacon coordinates have been decoded.
汽车人 下一个铁堡遗物的坐标已经破解
Ratchet, ready the ground bridge.
救护车 准备好环陆桥
Last one to the Omega key has to scrub the Energon tanks for a week.
最后一个摸到终极之钥的 倒一个礼拜能量废罐！
Didn't know we were keeping score.
我们还计分呢？
Arcee, Bumblebee, prepare to roll out.
阿尔茜 大黄蜂 准备出发！
Wait. What about me?
等等！那我呢？
Hum.
哼
I mean me and Bulkhead.
我是说 我和隔板呢？
The two of you will remain here
你们二人在此待命
in the event i'm able to decode a subsequent database entry before the others return.
以防我在他们回来之前就破译出下一个坐标
Optimus is right. Considering the very fate of Cybertron is at stake,
擎天柱是对的 考虑到塞博特恩的命运危在旦夕
response time is critical.
反应时间就至关重要
Keep your engines idling, kid.
敬候佳音吧 小子
Come on, Bee. Destiny awaits.
走吧 小蜂“宿命”在等着我们呢
We call it a pit stop.
这叫中场休息
We'll get back in the race.
咱们会回到赛场的
Over there.
在那儿
Well, well, just the Autobots I wanted to see.
看谁来了 正是人家所期待的呢
I'll handle the mad doctor. You grab the key.
我来对付变态医生 你去抢钥匙
I've been waiting to thank you both for all the memories.
人家正想为过往的回忆…感谢你们呢！
Who knew that sound waves could be such a.... Knockout?
谁能想到“声波”也有如此魅力…能“击倒”众生！
What's that, dear? I can't hear you!
脚步声太慌张了 我都能听到！
Bee, the relic!
小蜂 快抢遗物！
Scrap.
讨厌！
How low can it go?
这东西…也能这么用
Subwoofer or depth charge?
要么放手要么去死
Scrap.
糟了！
It appears identical to the one taken from me by Optimus Prime.
嗯…这个和擎天柱从我手中抢走的一模一样
as a means of sabotage.
好妨碍我们的行动？
Unlikely, my liege.
看起来不像 我的君王
They battled too desperately for it.
他们为夺此物简直是奋不顾身
Then pieces of a larger puzzle, perhaps.
或许 这只是整盘棋局里的一小步？
Excellent, Soundwave.
做得好 声波
Coordinates will shed some light on the subject.
运气好的话 这些新坐标会为我们理清头绪
Soundwave's on fire. And so I am.
声波真是锋头正劲啊 我也一样！
Keep your vanity in check, doctor.
别被虚荣冲昏了头脑 医生
Haven't I proven myself?!
难道我还没证明自己吗？
Your scientific expertise remains of greater use to me
对我而言 你更大的价值在于使用专业的科学技能
analyzing our latest acquisition.
来分析我们新的战利品
I must know what this relic is and what it can do.
我必须知道这是何物 有何用途
I'm sorry, Optimus.
对不起 擎天柱
Knockout was there, waiting for us.
击倒早就等在那里了
Seems the 'Cons are improving their decoding skills.
看来虎子们的破译水平提高了
And it seems that, with two keys already separated,
鉴于两块终极之钥已经分开
no one currently possesses the means to revive Cybertron.
眼下无人能让塞博特恩重现生机了
While our quest to restore our planet may have reached a stalemate,
尽管我们复兴故乡的工作陷入了僵局
securing the remaining keys is still the most prudent course of action.
保护好已有的终极之钥仍是当务之急
Man, it must have been crazy with Knockout going all sonic.
天啊 击倒还有那声波武器什么的一定很刺激！
Oh, I wish I'd been there. I would have...
我真希望当时也在场 好…
Would have what?
好什么？
Recovered the key like you did the first one?
好像上一次一样夺回钥匙？
Maybe. Who knows?
或许吧 谁知道呢？
I just want us to be firing on all cylinders,
我只是想把所见之物都轰成渣
you know, now that the Star Saber's gone.
你知道 我们已经失去了星辰剑
And I have a pretty good track record so far.
而我目前为止干得还不错
Look, kid, Arcee and Bumblebee are no slouches,
听着 小子 阿尔茜和大黄蜂并没有气馁
and Optimus managed just fine for eons without the big sword.
在没有那把大剑的漫长岁月中 擎天柱也一直做得很好
Of course, you wouldn't know about that.
当然 你不可能知道这些
And you've been locked in stasis the whole time we've been fighting this war.
当我们在此奋战之时 你还在外太空飘着呢！
Exactly, and I'm ready to make up for lost time.
所以！我已准备好弥补错失的时间了！
When Optimus says you're ready.
那得等擎天柱说你行才可以
You got to be in this for the long haul.
你要耐心等待
Slow and steady wins the race.
稳扎稳打才能赢得比赛
Hurry up, already!
啊…怎么还没好！
How is it possible that speed-enhancing Energon takes longer to process than regular Energon?!
提速能量怎么会比普通能量液化得更慢？！
An entire chunk of Red Energon, and this is all I get?!
整整一大块红色能量才液化成这么一丁点儿？
There's enough here for one dose, maybe two!
这顶多够我喝一口…最多两口！
While speed is hardly a suitable replacement for the might of the Apex armor,
超级速度或许代替不了精锐护甲的强大威力
it should provide me with enough of an edge to obtain a more formidable relic.
不过 却能让我在抢夺强大的先祖遗物时占尽先机
The next coordinates are ready.
下一个坐标破译了！
There remains one set left to decode.
那么只剩最后一个了
On it, boss.
马上就去 老大
I'm gonna bring back that key.
我一定会把钥匙带回来
Uh, Bulk?
嗯…小隔
Forgetting something?
是不是落下什么了？
Make sure you keep an eye on destiny's child, okay?
看好咱们的“宿命之子” 好吗？
Compared to watching Miko, piece of cake.
哈…跟照顾神子比起来 简直小菜一碟
Stick close. And stay focused.
靠近点 提高警惕
Gotcha!
我懂
I mean it.
我是认真的！
Me too.
我也是！
What is that?
那是什么声音？
One of the last sounds that you will ever hear.
是你丧钟的鸣响！
Dreadwing.
骇翼…
We got to get out of here, now!
我们得马上离开这儿 快！
Smoke, I'll handle Dreadwing. Go get the relic.
烟仔 我来对付骇翼 你快去拿遗物！
You got it.
没问题！
You love doing your dirty work from a distance, don't you?
你就喜欢躲在暗处放冷箭 对吧？
Too bad you don't have the ball bearings to fight up close and personal.
真可惜 你没种跟我堂堂正正地较量一番！
In this particular case,
就目前的情况而言
I will be all too happy to make an exception.
我很乐意为你破例！
An admirable effort,
你的努力值得夸奖
but you obviously forgot how our last encounter ended.
但你显然忘了咱们上次的交手是如何收场的
No, I didn't.
不 我没忘
Smoke, I'm on my way.
烟仔 我马上就来
Destiny.
我的宿命…
Smokescreen! Wake up!
烟幕！醒醒！
Wh-what happened?
呃…发生什么事了？
That's what I want to know.
我还想问你呢
The Omega key.
终极之钥！
I had it
我都拿到了！
until something hit me from behind.
直到什么东西从背后袭击了我…
Dreadwing must have had backup.
骇翼肯定有帮手
That relic's long gone.
那个遗物早就被带走了
Ratchet, we need a bridge.
救护车 打开环陆桥
I-I told Optimus I'd return with that key.
我…我答应过擎天柱会把钥匙带回去…
Listen, kid, Alpha Trion said we need all four keys
听着 孩子 钛师傅说过我们得把四个钥匙都弄到手
to restore Cybertron, remember?
才能让塞博特恩重生 记得吗？
We just need to hang on to the one we have
我们只要保护好手头上的
and find a way to get the others back from Megatron.
再想法从威震天那里把剩下的抢过来就行了
The promise of a new Cybertron in the palm of my hand...
塞博特恩重生的希望…掌握在我的手上
when I obtain all four.
只要我能集齐全部四把钥匙！
Smokescreen was sucker-punched.
烟幕是被人打了闷棍
Could have happened to any of us.
换了谁都会中招的
But it didn't,
事实并非如此！
because I was the one who dropped his guard.
分明是我放下了戒心
I was the one who blew it.
是我搞砸了任务
Some great warrior I'm turning out to be.
我这算哪门子的“伟大”战士
You still don't get it, do you?
你还是没搞懂 是吗？
A couple of victories aren't gonna make you a legend.
几次胜利是不足以让你成为传奇的
And not every mission results in success,
也不是每次任务都能成功
not for me, not for Bee, not even for Optimus.
我不能 小蜂不能 甚至包括擎天柱在内
We've gained relics, and we've lost some.
我们得到了一些遗物 也失去了一些
We've also lost friends. We've even lost a world.
我们还失去过朋友 甚至失去了一个世界
But this is one time we get a do-over.
但是 这一次我们可以从头再来
We have a chance to bring back Cybertron,
现在我们有机会让塞博特恩重生
and everyone in this room needs to be in sync.
这是在场的每个人的事！
This isn't about you or your destiny.
而不是你一个人的“宿命”
Arcee, you have made your point.
阿尔茜 你说得够清楚了
Optimus, he needs to hear this.
擎天柱 他需要彻底明白
You might actually become a great warrior one day,
或许有一天 你真的成为了一名伟大的战士
and I sincerely hope that you do.
我真心希望如此
But greatness begins and ends with putting the team first,
但以团队为重才能造就伟大
not your personal scorecard.
只顾个人表现是行不通的！
There's nothing I wouldn't do for you guys.
我愿意为大家做任何事！
Then stop trying to be a hero
那就别总去逞英雄了
and start being an Autobot.
先学着当一个汽车人吧
You know what?
你知道吗？
Maybe I'm just not good enough.
或许是我还不够优秀！
Next time Optimus advises you to stop,
下回擎天柱建议你打住的时候
perhaps you should listen.
你或许应该听他的
I'll bring him back.
我去把他叫回来
Smokescreen is young, Bulkhead,
烟幕还年轻 隔板
and has much to learn,
还有很多东西要学
but right now he needs to clear his thoughts.
不过现在 他需要理清一下思绪
And I need to finish decoding the final Iacon entry.
我则需要破译最后一个铁堡坐标
You never even spied the relic?!
你竟然连遗物的影子都没瞅着？！
By the time I reached the location, it was gone,
当我到达时 它已经不见了…
as were the Autobots.
汽车人也不见了
It would serve us well to not only decode the final Iacon entry before Optimus Prime does,
优秀的忠仆不仅能抢在擎天柱之前 破译最后一件遗物的位置
but to recapture those relics currently held by the Autobots.
还能抢回汽车人手中的那些！
Soundwave. Despite your primary task,
声波 把你的主要工作先放一放
I trust that you have been making progress pinpointing the location of their base.
我相信对汽车人基地的定位 你已取得进展
Good. Given the recent accumulation of evidence,
很好 根据最近得到的线索
we possess a clearer idea of where their human colleagues reside.
我们已掌握了他们的人类同伙的确切位置
And Laserbeak should soon determine whether the Autobots dwell in proximity.
激光鸟应该很快就能抵近汽车人的藏身之处
Ah. The final entry has been decoded.
啊 最后一组坐标也破解了
Has it?
你确定？
Perhaps it's a layer of secondary encryption.
唔…可能还有一层二级加密
The coordinates are forming an image.
坐标正在形成一幅图像
Why would the final Iacon entry be different from the others?
为何最后的铁堡记录会如此与众不同呢？
Maybe it's a picture of the relic.
没准儿这是遗物的图？
Of what possible use could that be to us without knowing its location?
不知道地点的话 光要这图能有什么用？
I trust that Alpha Trion has his reasons.
我相信钛师傅自有原因
Smokescreen?
这是烟幕？！
Prime's latest recruit
擎天柱的新兵…
is the final relic of Iacon?
是最后一个铁堡遗物？
Is this that hotshot's idea of a joke?
…那会是激射开的玩笑吗？
Maybe he knows where the key is.
没准儿烟幕知道钥匙在哪儿！
And never bothered to mention it?
…那他只是懒得说了？
A more likely possibility
最可能的情况是
is that Smokescreen himself somehow is the key, without knowing it.
烟幕本身就是那个钥匙 而他自己却不知情！
Whatever the case, he could be in grave danger.
无论如何 他现在的处境都极度危险！
Smokescreen, return to base immediately.
烟幕 立刻返回基地！
He may have deactivated his comm link.
他可能关掉通讯器了
Locate his position and prepare the ground bridge.
锁定他的位置 开启环陆桥！
It seems our side project is already paying off.
看来我们的次要计划 已经有回报了
You picked the wrong day to mess with me, 'Con.
老子今天心情不好 虎子！
Smokescreen.
烟幕…
No!
不！